Boys, starting today,
we begin high-altitude bombing trials.
We'll climb to 30,000 feet,
well ahead of the target sector
above the clouds
and out of their missile range.
But remember, no one in the world
has ever attempted this in the mountains.
The peaks we want to target have flat tops
that are not more than 200 meters wide.
We have dumb bombs
that are as fast as jets,
So, the release altitude, jet speed,
and GPS position should be accurate.
Then the bomb will land
on this narrow 200-meter target.
If the release is even a second late,
the bomb will miss the target peak
and land in the valley.
And if we're in a hurry
and release the bombs early,
the bomb will fall
into the valley before hitting the target,
exactly where
our own army will be sitting.
So, boys, neither we nor our machines
can fail in this mission.
Man and machine will have to work as one.
Tridents, check position.
Hercules 2.
Hercules 2. Joker.
Did you say "Hercules"?
Please confirm.
Correction. I'm sorry.
I meant,
Trident approaching release point.
Hercules was Ahuja's call sign, right?
Yes, sir.
Probably a slip of the tongue.
Trident releasing bombs in five,
four,
three,
two,
one… Now.
Bombs away.
Seven forty.
Bomb off target. Radial error 1230.
Bomb off target, sir. Radial error 1230.
Linear error 740 meters.
Let's keep going.
Let's see how much difference
the other sorties show.
Five, four, three, two, one, now!
Bombs away!
Bomb off target.
You're a long way off, Tony.
Linearly and radially.
Sir, there are
a lot more variables to factor in.
We'll get there soon.
Your soon is already
too late for the Army.
I want a hard commitment.
-A week, ten days, just--
-Three days, sir.
We'll be ready in three days.
All right.
If it takes a fourth day,
then I will consider this trial a failure.
Sir.
What happened? Do you want to back out?
Everyone outside this room
thinks this strategy is useless.
If you guys also feel the same, tell me.
Sir, none of us
doubt this strategy.
With so many parameters
and met chart extrapolations,
if we hadn't hard-committed to three days,
then, sir, I think we had a chance.
Exactly, sir.
For such complex calculations,
three days is practically insufficient.
Our army has been fighting there
for the past month.
And you think three days isn't enough?
Are you guys aware that,
just to recapture
some of the peaks of Tololing Complex,
they've been fighting for three weeks?
Do you know how many senior officers
and soldiers have lost their lives?
At an altitude of 16,000 feet,
at minus ten degrees, with low oxygen,
they are climbing with 25 kilograms of
ammunition and rations on their backs.
They have no cover.
They are directly in the line of fire.
Before climbing,
they think about reducing their rations
so they can carry more ammunition.
It'll be more useful.
And if after crawling all night long
and dodging enemy bullets,
they manage to reach there,
they need energy for hand-to-hand combat.
Where will they get it from?
Despite knowing all this,
they are still fighting.
They're fighting
to avenge their martyred brothers.
They are fighting to tell
the Pakistan Army and politicians,
"We will not hand over
our mountains to you on a platter."
The Indian Army is taking a beating,
but you guys feel--
Sir, we'll do it.
Come what may, we'll do this.
-Boys?
-We'll do it, sir!
The Indian Army is depending
on the Indian Air Force,
and the Indian Air Force, on us.
Do all the calculations you need to do.
You have 72 hours, not three days.
And this time,
neither our machines nor we can fail.
We owe this to Ahuja.
Arrows, let's set up a proper workflow.
We'll need weather data
from the Met Department.
But I gave Chou sir all the data for June.
Not just this June, we want data
for every June for the last ten years.
I will feed all the data
into the computer with the other variables
to calculate the ideal bomb release point.
We'll keep calculating,
we'll keep dropping bombs.
And we'll keep at it till we get it right.
Griffin, bombs away.
Bombs away!
Arrow, bombs away!
What the hell are we missing, guys?
What the hell are we missing?
Sir, all parameters are accounted for.
Wind speed, temperature, met charts--
Baldy, your calculations
are absolutely correct.
But our bombs are still landing
ahead of the target.
Sir, there's one thing.
At an altitude of 30,000 feet,
the air becomes thinner.
Right, sir.
Air density.
Baldy, multiply the air density formula
by rho over rho-zero.
Sir.
-Sangy.
-Jai Hind, sir.
-Welcome back.
-Thank you, sir.
Dhali?
Hercules 2, breaking off.
Everybody needs help, Dhali.
Hercules 2, fuel check.
Should've released by now.
Check status.
Trident, check position.
Trident, release point overshot.
I'm sorry. May I do another pass?
What is Dhali doing?
Tell him to come back.
Negative, Trident. Return to base.
Trident returning to base.
Adonis, bombs away.
Now! Bombs away!
Bombs away!
Sir, linear error 450 meters.
And radially,
we're sharp at twelve o'clock.
Let's do one thing, Baldy.
Let's fine-tune the forward-throw formula.
That's how we'll get this right.
Sure, sir.
I told him to look
at the forward-throw formula.
Yes, Dhali?
Sir, I got distracted
in the air for a few seconds, sir.
Distract?
Sir, the…
The fuel meter--
Dhali, you know as much as I do.
Right now,
there's no room for distraction.
Even a minor mistake
in the actual operation,
and the bomb could land on our own army.
I understand, sir. It won't happen again.
I can't let you fly right now.
For your sake.
And for everyone else's sake.
Sir, there is concerning news
from Southeast Asia.
Indian Air Force is doing
high-altitude bombing trials.
What the hell was that, Zinni?
They're trying GPS guidance
on their stone-age MiG-21s.
Jesus Christ.
If the Indian Air Force
gets back in there,
this whole fucking mess
could blow up in our face.
Their trials will not succeed, sir.
Pentagon's been monitoring.
I got it covered.
We'd better take care of this.
One misstep and this whole thing
could go nuclear in no time.
You got that right, sir.
Releasing bombs in three, two, one…
Now! Griffin, bombs away!
Flying Officer Baldy.
Error 370 meters, sir.
Who's next?
Sangy?
Yes, sir.
Releasing bombs in five,
four,
three, two, one…
Now! Adonis, bombs away!
Linear error 360 meters, sir.
We have time for one more sortie, right?
Let's go, sir.
Tony, your calculations
are absolutely correct.
But I don't know what other error
is creeping in at that height.
-Hey, Baldy?
-Sir.
Call the Met Department again.
Check if there's any variation
in today's forecast and our chart.
Sir, I've been taking hourly updates
from the Met Department.
Everything's cross-checked. No difference.
We've done all these calculations
on paper. Maybe you're missing something.
Some data entry, some variable,
some parameter, something.
You gave your best, Tony.
But this strategy is not working.
I'm proud of you all, boys,
for even attempting this.
But it's time to…
call it off.
Steady.
Dhali?
Dhali, stop it, man.
Our bombing trials have failed.
So?
Dhali, we're all feeling Ahuja sir's loss.
I can understand
what's going on inside you.
Were you there?
Were you two there?
Were any of you there with Ahuja sir,
up in the air?
No, no, there wasn't.
Then you won't understand.
-Hello, ma'am.
-Yes?
Mrs. Alka Ahuja?
I'm from the Maruti showroom.
Your husband had booked an 800 for you.
Congratulations.
I have registration papers that--
Leave them here. I'll get them signed
and sent to the showroom.
Have a nice day. Thank you.
I forgot to smile.
Whenever Ajay used to go for a sortie,
I always sent him off with a smile.
But the day he left for Srinagar…
Let's go.
Sir, there is no need
for servicing right now.
That's why I've put
the ground crew on standby.
Do we have a handheld GPS?
Yes, sir. We should.
Get it.
Right, sir.
Chou, we're on the tarmac, but coordinates
being displayed are of the runway.
Look at this.
This GPS error is exactly 250 meters.
Sir, the USA has tried
to sabotage our trials, sir.
What?
Sir, as you know,
our GPS signals
come through the US Air Force.
My hunch is
that they've degraded our GPS signal.
Our calculations
are absolutely correct, sir.
They've degraded our GPS signal
with the help of their satellites,
and that's why errors are showing up.
Sir, I have checked
with a GPS device at different places.
This error is exactly 250 meters.
We can account for it.
I'm still waiting for the good news, Tony.
Sir, for that,
we will need that fourth day.
If we release the bomb a little earlier
at the same release angle,
we can accommodate the GPS lag.
Releasing bombs in three, two, one…
Now! Arrow, bombs away!
One-twenty.
Bomb almost on target.
Error 120 meters only.
Jai Hind!
Jai Hind.
Sir,
error only 120 meters.
-Sir.
-Good job done, Tony!
-Thank you, sir.
-I'm glad I gave you that fourth day.
Sir, at first, our soldiers
could only see the mountains,
not their army.
Now their army will only see the clouds,
not us.
In the evening, we'll meet the Army
in Drass to get coordinates,
and inform them
that Operation Safed Sagar is back.
Sir.
Sir, Point 5140 is the highest peak
in the Tololing sector of West Kargil.
We're facing our heaviest casualties here.
The enemy has choked
our valley with this peak.
So, we want you to start
by bombing this area.
Because in the Drass sector, recapturing
Point 5140 is the most difficult task.
They are able to directly target
our National Highway 1
and block the supplies from there.
And that's why it's critical
to recapture this peak
so as to restore our supply chain.
Okay, Sartaj. You'll give us
coordinates of Point 5140 for the bombing.
And for coordination
between the Army and Air Force,
we'll deploy
a forward air controller there
who will stay with your forward troops.
He will also convert target coordinates
and relay the real-time location
of both sides.
Sir, I think Baldy is best suited
for this technical job.
Sir.
That's it, then.
Operation Safed Sagar resumes with 5140.
Good night.
-Jai Hind, sir.
-Jai Hind.
Amidst international pressure
and widespread condemnation of
Squadron Leader Ahuja's brutal killing,
Pakistan has released
the second captured
Indian Air Force pilot.
In the latest from South Asia,
Pakistan has rebuffed American attempts to
mediate in the escalating Kargil conflict,
insisting it remains a bilateral matter
between Islamabad and New Delhi.
Foreign Minister Sartaj Aziz is now
traveling to India for direct talks
with his counterpart, Jaswant Singh.
Vajpayee sahib,
Mian sahib
and the entire cabinet of Pakistan
deeply regret
the martyrdom of your soldiers
and the passing away of pilot Ajay Ahuja.
We thought that the impact
of the jet crash killed him,
but it seems
he fell into the hands of Mujahideen.
Mian sahib has ordered us
to personally speak to Mujahideen
so that the matter cools down.
That's why we sent
your pilot Nishant back safely.
I am prepared to continue
mediating with Mujahideen.
But this mediation
can only take place when India
is ready to hold discussions
on the Kashmir issue.
Vajpayee sahib, you should trust Pakistan.
I have faith, Aziz sahib,
that it is only Pakistan
that can resolve this matter.
Sir, India has deployed
15,000 more soldiers in the Kargil sector.
Whether it's 1,000 or 15,000,
what difference does it make, Aziz?
It's been over three weeks
since we were discovered.
Has anyone done us any damage?
As long as we hold the height advantage,
we'll keep crushing
both their Army and their Air Force.
Sir, I tried everything,
but he's very stubborn, sir.
If he's stubborn,
then make an example of him.
Make such an example of him
that before they even think of entering
Pakistan, their blood runs cold.
Sir, what about
the international community?
Screw the international community.
Such an important call
on an unsecured line?
There is a limit to things, Sartaj sahib.
This even by
Pakistani standards is pathetic.
We became acquainted
with General Musharraf's innate character
during the peace talks itself.
But now it's clear, uniform or sherwani,
you are all of the same innate character.
Aziz sahib,
go and tell your Mian sahib,
the time for discussion
and dialogue is now over.
Now, India
will only respond
on the battlefields of the Kargil War.
Foreign Minister Jaswant Singh
and Pakistan's Sartaj Aziz
are emerging after a two-hour meeting.
But as you can see, journalists' questions
are going unanswered.
Why didn't they let him
speak to the press?
I am bringing
the nation's biggest story to you.
The foreign ministry has released
phone records this morning,
in which Pakistan's Army Chief,
General Pervez Musharraf's voice
can be clearly heard.
These recordings once again make it clear
that the invasion in Kargil
was not led by Mujahideen alone,
and that the entire operation
is the Pakistan Army's doing.
We are following
extraordinary developments in South Asia,
where leaked telephone conversations
have fundamentally altered the narrative
surrounding the Kargil conflict.
These intercepted conversations
between Pakistani Army Chief,
General Pervez Musharraf,
and his second-in-command
offer unprecedented insight
into what appears to be
a systematic deception
campaign by Islamabad.
Sorry.
-I came without giving you notice--
-Mian sahib…
First of all, I would like to sincerely
apologize to the entire cabinet
for the trouble you've faced
because of the leaked tapes.
I shouldn't have spoken
on an unsecured line.
Come, please sit.
Forget the tapes.
When China is with us,
what does it matter what
the rest of the world thinks about us?
Right?
China is with us, right?
Yes, sir.
Of course.
General Musharraf,
Chinese officials have confirmed to us
that they never extended any support
to you in this operation.
Fear the Lord, Pervez mian.
How many more lies will you tell?
To the entire cabinet,
to the Prime Minister?
To the entire public? How much?
In the politics of our Pakistan,
the Kashmir issue
is a very thorny issue.
Everyone wants Kashmir,
but no one wants to undertake
the responsibility of getting it.
If I hadn't fulfilled my responsibility
by telling this lie,
would we have gotten
such a big piece of Kashmir?
No, we wouldn't have!
Mian sahib,
you'd have buckled
under America's pressure
and stopped the operation a long time ago.
What I should have done
after the 17th May briefing,
I am doing today.
I'm putting an end
to Operation Mountaineering right now.
Effective immediately.
Now our country
will not suffer the consequences
of General Musharraf's unauthorized war.
It's an order.
February 23, 1999, Skardu Base.
The Prime Minister
was given a full briefing
on Mujahideen Operation "Tupac."
I'm sure
you remember this picture, Mian sahib.
It is from two days after the peace talks.
In that meeting, the PM approved
Stinger missile supplies for the soldiers,
which we used to target Indian jets.
This is your signature, right, Mian sahib?
Everything happened
with your approval, Mian sahib.
If you still think otherwise,
let's call the press tomorrow morning,
and present our versions of the truth.
This war was not started
by Pervez Musharraf.
Our war with India
has been going on since partition.
But the difference this time,
is that we are winning the war.
I want to inform the cabinet
that Pakistan's Army will not retreat
from a war that's already been won.
Whether Islamabad stands with us
or not.
Sir, Sangy and I went to
the blast pen. All set.
And what about the men?
Are they rested well?
I'll just be back.
Can I fly tomorrow, sir?
I really need to, sir.
-Look, Dhali, it's really not--
-Sir, please.
I wish I could help you.
Jai Hind, sir.
Jai Hind.
You have to go back.
Everybody needs help, Dhali.
Yes, Dhali?
Hercules 2, coordinates.
Everybody needs help, Dhali.
Hercules 2, breaking off.
Hercules 2, fuel check.
Dhali?
At ease.
It wasn't your fault.
"Why was I low on fuel?"
"Why did I come back?"
"Had I not returned,
Ahuja sir would still be alive."
This is what you're thinking, right?
Stop thinking.
Sir, if I wasn't at fault,
why am I not able to face Alka ma'am?
I was at fault, sir.
I used to say big things.
"I'll do this during war."
"I'll do that." Sir, what have I done?
I took a U-turn and came back.
Sir, every time I close my eyes, all I see
is that fuel meter and nothing else, sir.
Why didn't he let me go with him, sir?
When the time came, I took a U-turn, sir.
I did nothing.
This war isn't over yet, Dhali.
Tomorrow, we are going to bomb 5140,
the most critical peak in Drass.
This will be my life's
and perhaps this mission's
most important sortie.
And I want my best pilot with me.
Will you fly with me?
Tell me.
Now the sports news.
Today, India will clash against Pakistan
in the Super Six match in Manchester.
Both batsmen out on the field,
as we await play to begin.
Tendulkar joined by Ramesh
who replaces an injured Ganguly.
And we're underway with a hard,
new English ball in Wasim Akram's grip
up against the finest batsmen
on the planet.
Scanners to FAC,
Arrow formation has taken off.
Sartaj sir, they've taken off.
-Chanakya to Sangram. Over.
-Sangram for Chanakya. Okay, pass. Over.
Eagles incoming.
Stand by for attack.
Roger. Over.
-Climbing to 30,000 feet.
-Roger. On your tail.
What the hell?
Arrow 1, your speed is fluctuating.
All okay?
I have a problem, Arrow 2.
My Air Speed Indicator is misbehaving.
Looks like a pitot tube blockage.
We should abort this mission.
-But, Arrow 1, can I drop my bomb?
-Negative, Arrow 2.
Without air speed indication,
I'm blind.
You have to guide me back to the base now.
We have to abort the mission. Now.
Sir, there's been some technical glitch.
They're aborting the mission.
-Chanakya for Sangram. Over.
-Sangram for Chanakya. Okay, pass, over.
Hold position. Eagles aborting.
Company, hold.
Down the track he comes, lofts it skywards
and that's taken!
Saqlain Mushtaq catches a single one
at extra cover
and Pakistan have their prized wicket.
Chin up, soldier.
Sir, we don't need to abort the mission.
If I can guide you to the base,
I can guide you on the bombing too, sir.
Too risky for that, Dhali.
I've told you this before,
bombs could land on our own army.
Sir, you just match my speed and position.
I will be your airspeed indicator.
It's too risky, Dhali.
This isn't Tosa Maidan.
The stakes are too high.
Sir, you said
that I'm your best pilot.
I won't let you down, sir.
I've taken a U-turn once.
I won't do it again.
We have to do this for Hercules 1.
All right, fine. Let's do this.
-For Ahuja.
-Yes, sir.
Sir, they're coming in for a second pass.
Chanakya for Sangram.
Eagles are coming back.
Stand by to attack. Over.
Roger, sir. Jai Hind.
Up in the air.
And Afridi has spilled
it at deep mid-wicket.
That will go down as a dropped chance
and a boundary…
Ready the missiles! It's time to fight!
Come on, get the SAMs ready! Move forward!
Two minutes from release point, sir.
Stay steady on my left echelon.
And try to match my exact position.
Roger. Matching position.
You're falling a little behind.
A touch of power. 2%.
Power increased by 2%.
In position.
-Maintain position.
-Maintaining.
Arrow 1, now turn right three degrees.
Turning right three degrees.
Come closer, sir.
Maintain position at half wingspan.
Coming in. Half wingspan.
We're only 60 seconds away
from release point.
The true air speed
for bomb release should be 850.
Let's increase now.
Roger. Increasing.
Maintaining position.
Thirty seconds left.
Lock throttle now.
Throttle locked.
Arming switches now.
Switches armed.
Standby to release in ten,
nine,
eight,
seven,
six,
five,
four,
three,
two, one…
Now! Bombs away!
Bombs away!
Retreat!
Yes!
Chanakya for Sangram. Over.
Bombing successful!
The sky is raining fire.
-Hail…
-Goddess Durga!
-Mother India!
Oh, yeah!
After losing three aircraft
and five pilots
in the first two days
of Operation Safed Sagar,
the Indian Air Force
has staged a spectacular comeback.
The Air Force's MiG-21 jets
have carried out strikes
in difficult mountainous terrain,
clearing the way for the Army.
No other air force in the world
could have opened this path.
And after weeks of…
-Here.
-The doctor forbade it.
All okay?
The Indian Army captured Point 5140.
Yeah. I'll be all okay.
The intruders still have
control over some hills…
But today's victory
is not just a comeback.
This is the declaration of the intent
India has made.
This war is now heading in one direction,
and that direction is towards home.
How many months?
It's been a month now.
Congratulations!
When did you find out?
A week ago.
Why didn't you tell me?
I felt the time wasn't right.
This is good news, Madhavi.
There is no right or wrong time for this.
Have you told Baldy?
-No.
-Why?
I'll tell him the day
he doesn't have a sortie.
Hassan, what is this message you've sent?
"Fire is raining from the sky"?
What do you mean?
It's the last message
from our soldiers at 5140.
They were listening to cricket commentary
when it started raining bombs.
What were our Stingers doing?
Sir, they didn't see the Indian jets,
they only heard their sound.
How can this be, Hassan?
No air force in the world
can attack from such heights.
I don't know how.
But the Indian Air Force is doing it, sir.
We took away, we took away
We took away Tololing
We will take away, we will take away
We will take away Tiger Hill too!
We will take away!
Boys!
Today, after weeks of fighting,
we've captured Point 5140
and hoisted the tricolor on the peak!
But…
we all know how many of our brothers
have laid down their lives
to capture this peak.
Their sacrifice won't be in vain.
This war is not over yet.
For our brothers,
in memory of our brothers,
in honor of our brothers,
we will fight!
We will fight, sir!
We'll keep fighting, sir!
And we will hoist the tricolor
on every peak that is rightfully ours!
Right?
-Hail…
-Mother India!
If we keep bombing peak by peak like this,
who knows how long this war will last.
Yeah.
We have to scale up, sir.
For our army, for these soldiers.
I agree with you, Tony.
But Golden Arrows only has eight jets.
And only those eight jets
have in-built GPS systems.
If we try to fit them into others,
it could take months.
I know that, sir.
Tony…
I have an idea.
With the support of Golden Arrows'
successful GPS bombing,
the Army has recaptured a strategic post.
And that's why we have to scale up
what Golden Arrows has started.
You've all been given handheld GPS sets,
which we have sourced from
the electronics market across the country.
They're not as perfect
as the MiG-21's built-in GPS,
but when have we ever waited
for perfect conditions?
Now we will bomb day and night.
Wear them on your wrists, on your thighs,
or put them on the cockpit walls,
Stick them wherever you feel right.
But make sure you drop hell on those rats
from every direction.
In five, four,
three, two,
one… Now!
-Bombs away!
Go!
Bombs away!
-Sir, long live Pakistan.
-Long live.
What's the update?
-Sir, morale is down.
-Why?
News of the bombing
has spread to other peaks.
The soldiers are scared.
Why are they scared?
When the enemy jets were dropping bombs,
what were your soldiers doing?
Sir, as I told you on the phone,
they came from above the clouds.
Our soldiers could not
operate the Stingers.
Hassan, why are sangars built of stones?
Inform every peak
that if the sound of enemy jets is heard,
then all the soldiers
should hide in the sangars.
-Copy, sir.
-Let's go.
Bombing successful. Move ahead!
Move!
Subtitle translation by: Monika Saraf